Finding Aid for the Anti-Slavery Pamphlet Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Longyear, J. W. Speech of Hon. J. W. Longyear of Michigan, on the Reconstruction of the Union. Washington D.C, April 13, 1864 (Folder 165)
- Thayer, Russell. Speech of Hon. Russell Thayer of Pennsylvania, on The Bill to Guarantee to Certain States Whose Governments have Been Overthrown, A Republican Form of Government. April 30, 1864. Washington D.C. McGill & Witherow (Folder 166)
- Williams, Thomas. Speech of Hon. Thomas Williams of Pennsylvania, On The Restoration of the Union, April 28, 1864 (Folder 167)
- Perham, Sidney. Speech of Hon. Sidney Perham, of Maine, the Slaveholders’ Rebellion and Modern Democracy. Washington D.C, May 3, 1864 (Folder 168)
- Garfield, James A. Treason in Congress: Speech of Hon. James A. Garfield of Ohio, in reply to the Speech of Hon. Alexander Long in Favor of Abandoning the War and Recognizing the Southern Confederacy. Washington D.C, April 8, 1864 (Folder 169)
- Commonwealth of Massachusetts: Public Document 31, 33, 35. Reports of the Guardians of the Chappequiddic, Christiantown, Troy, Mashpee, and Dudley Indians, September 30, 1864 (Folder 170)
- Beaman, F. C. Speech of Hon. F.C. Beaman, of Michigan, In the House of Representatives, March 22, 1864 (Folder 171)
- Vindex. Mr. Gladstone, “The Times” and Democracy. London, 1864 (Folder 172)
- Smith, Goldwin. Letter to A Whig Member of the Southern Independence Association. Boston, 1864 (Folder 173)
- Murphy, D.F. Presidential Election, 1864: Proceedings of the National Union Convention. June 7, New York: Baker & Godwin (Folder 174)
- Whiting, William. Opinions of Slavery and Reconstruction of the Union as Expressed by President Lincoln with brief notes by Hon. William Whiting. John A. Gray & Green, 1864 (Folder 175)
- Union League Club. Report on Volunteering, October 13, 1864 (Folder 176)
- Broom, W.D. An Englishman’s Thoughts on the Crimes of the South and the Recompense of the North. New York: Loyal Publication Society, 1865 (Folder 177)
- De Gasparin, A. Reconstruction, a Letter to President Johnson. Loyal Publication Society, Number 87. New York, 1865 (Folder 178)
- Smith, Gerrit. Gerrit Smith on Rebellion.Volume II. New York, 1865 (Folder 179)
- Phillips, Wendell. Remarks of Wendell Phillips, at the Mass Meeting of Workingmen in Faneuil Hall, November 2, 1865. Boston: Voice Printing and Publishing Company (Folder 180)
- Kelley, William D. Speech of Hon. William D. Kelley of Pennsylvania, in support of His Proposed Amendment to the Bill ‘To Guarantee to Certain States, Whose Governments Have Been Usurped or Overthrown, a Republican Form of Government.’, January 16, 1865 (Folder 181)
- Boutwell, George S. Reconstruction: Its true Basis. July 4, 1865. Boston: Wright & Potter (Folder 182)
- Julian, George W. Radicalism and Conservatism: the Truth of History Vindicated. Speech of Hon. George W. Julian of Indiana, in the House Of Representatives, February 7, 1865 (Folder 183)
- Commonwealth of Massachusetts: Public Documents 31-34, Reports of the Chappequiddic, Christiantown, Dudley, Natick and Troy Indians, and of the Treasurer of Herring Pond Plantation, September 30, 1865 (Folder 184)
- House Message 227. Commonwealth of Massachusetts, April 17, 1865 (Folder 185)
- Senate Report 156. Commonwealth of Massachusetts, March 29, 1865 (Folder 186)
- Kelley, William D. The Equality of all Men before the Law Claimed and Defended in Speeches by Hon. Wm. D. Kelley, Wendell Phillips, and Frederick Douglas, and Letters from Elizur Wright and Wm. Heighton. Boston, 1865 (Folder 187)
- Scenes in the War of 1812, Defense of New Orleans. From Harper’s Magazine, January 1865 (Folder 188)
- Official Documents Relating to a Chaplain’s Campaign (Not) with General Butler But in New York. Lowell: Charles Hunt, Printer, 1865 (Folder 189)
- The Record of the Democratic Party, 1860-1865 (Folder 190)
- Thompson, Joseph. Memorial Service for Three Hundred Thousand Union Soldiers, with a Commemorative Discourse. New York, 1866 (Folder 191)
- Commonwealth of Massachusetts: Public Documents 29-34. Reports of the Guardians of the Chappequiddic, Christiantown, Dudley, Natick, and Troy Indians, and the Report of the Treasurer of Herring Pond Plantation, September 30, 1866 (Folder 192)
- Atkinson, W.P. Dynamic and Mechanic Teaching: A Lecture Read Before the American Institute of Instruction, New Haven, August 9, 1865. Cambridge: Sever & Francis, 1866 (Folder 193)
- Address of [the Union League Club of New York’s President], June 23, 1866 (Folder 194)
- Commonwealth of Massachusetts: Public Documents 30-34. Reports of the Guardians of the Chappequiddic, Christiantown, Dudley, Mashpee, and Natick Indians, and the Report of the Treasurer of the Herring Pond Plantation, September 30, 1867 (Folder 195)
- Moody, Loring. A Plain Statement to All Honest Democrats. Boston: Rand & Avery, 1868 (Folder 196)
- Commonwealth of Massachusetts: Public Documents 30-33. Reports of the Guardians of the Chappequiddic, Christiantown, Dudley, and Mashpee Indians, and the Report of the Treasurer of the Herring Pond Plantation, September 30, 1868 (Folder 197)
- Washburn, Emory. American Social Science Association: Law As an Element of Social Science. A Paper Read at the Fourth Annual Meeting, October 14, 1868. American Social Science Association. Boston (Folder 198)
- Statement of Operations in the Museum of the University of Michigan in the Department of Geology, Zoology, and Botany and the Department of Archeology and Relics for the Year Ending, September 25, 1868 (Folder 199)
- Heinzen, Karl. The True Character of Humboldt. Oration, Delivered at the German Humboldt Festival in Boston. Indianapolis, 1869 (Folder 200)
- Commonwealth of Massachusetts: Senate 19. Report from Oliver Warner, Secretary of the Commonwealth, January 20, 1869 (Folder 201)
- Commonwealth of Massachusetts: House 483.Matters Dealing with the Indians of the Commonwealth, June 3, 1869 (Folder 202)
- Address of His Excellency William Claflin, to the Two Branches of the Legislature of Massachusetts. Boston, January 9, 1869 (Folder 203)
- Beesley, Edward Spencer. Letters to The Working Classes. London: High Holborn. London: Holborn, 1869 (Folder 204)
- Hervet, M. Emile. L’Ethnographie de la Pologne. Notice sur Les Travaux de Madame Severine Duchinska. Paris, 1869 (Folder 205)
- Smith, Goldwin. The Relations between America and England, an Address Delivered Before the Citizens of Ithaca. Ithaca:NewYork, May 19, 1869 (Folder 206)
- Mayo, A.D. Religion in the Common Schools, Three Lectures. Cincinnati, October 1869 (Folder 207)
- Congreve, Richard. Our Foreign Policy. London: Holborn, 1870 (Folder 208)
- Commonwealth of Massachusetts: House 13, from the Attorney General’s Office to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, January 18, 1870 (Folder 209)
- Commonwealth of Massachusetts: Senate 14. Report of the Committee of the Legislature of 1869, on the Condition of the Gay Head Indians, January 1870 (Folder 210)
- Campbell, Robert. General Rules and Administrative Regulations of the International Working-Men’s Association. London: Holborn, 1871 (Folder 211)
- Phillips, Wendell. The People Coming to Power: Speech of Wendell Phillips at the Salisbury Beach Gathering. Boston: Lee & Shepard, 1871 (Folder 212)
- Hervet, Emil. Ethnographie Polens. Bericht uber die Arbeiten der Frau Severine Duchinska. Wein, 1871 (Folder 213)
- Proceedings of the Boston & Oswego Railroad Convention. Held in Oswego. June 14 & 15, 1871. Oswego: New York (Folder 214)
- Pare, William. Report of Proceedings of The Festival in Commemoration of The Centenary Birthday of Robert Owen, the Philanthropist, Also, Mr. Owen’s Outline of the Rational System of Society. London: High Holborn, 1871 (Folder 215)
- Meslier, Jean. Biology versus Theology. The Cure Meslier and His Will, from the German of Strauss; with Preliminary Remarks by Julian, 1871 (Folder 216)
- Taft, S.H. A Discourse on The Character and Death of John Brown. Des Moines, December 12, 1859 (Folder 217)
- Waterhouse, S. The Advantages of Educated Labor in Missouri. St. Louis, April 26, 1872 (Folder 218)
- Ware, John F. W. An Oration before the City Authorities of Boston. July 4, 1873. Boston (Folder 219)
- Elliott, Robert B. Sumner Memorial Meeting. Oration of Hon. Robert B. Elliot M. C. of South Carolina, Delivered… Under the Auspices of the Colored Citizens of Boston, 1874 (Folder 220)
- Pascoe, Charles E. A Prohibitory Law of Massachusetts versus the Licensing Law of England, with an Account of the Latter. Boston: Rockwell & Churchill, 1874 (Folder 221)
- Northrop, Birdsey Grant. Education Abroad, an Other Papers. New York and Chicago: Barnes & Co., 1874 (Folder 222)
- Missing (Folder 223)
- Winthrop, Robert C. Oration Delivered Before the City Council and Citizens of Boston, on the One Hundredth Anniversary of the Declaration of American Independence, July 4, 1876 (Folder 224)
- Kellogg, H. Speeches on Dr. Samuel Gridley Howe and Mr. William Cullen Bryant. Boston, 1876 (Folder 225)
- The Western. Report on a Course of Study from Primary School to University. Vol. II, Numbers 9-34, September, 1876 (Folder 226)
- The Western, The Sphinx Riddles of Education, November, 1877 (Folder 227)
- M.M. A Plan for the Relief of the Trading and Working Classes When out of Employment. London: Kent & Co., 1879 (Folder 228)
- Phillips, Wendell. The Scholar in the Republic, Address at the Centennial Anniversary of the Phi Beta Kappa of Harvard College.. Boston, June 30, 1881 (Folder 229)
- 200th Anniversary of One of the Grandest Events in History. John Sobieski, King of Poland, Conquers the Turks Under the Walls of Vienna, September 12, 1683, and Forever After Relieves the Whole Christian World from the iron Yoke of the Turks, September 12, 1883 (Folder 230)
- Anderson, Charles. Texas, Before, and on the Eve of the Rebellion. A Paper Read Before the Cincinnati Society of Ex-Army and Navy Officers. January 3rd, 1884 (Folder 231)
- Phillips, Wendell. Oration delivered in the Old South Meeting-House. June 14, 1876 Boston, 1884 (Folder 232)
- Birney, James G. The American Churches: The Bulwarks of American Slavery. Concord, New Hampshire, 1885 (Folder 233)
- McKinley, William. Abraham Lincoln. An Address by William McKinley of Ohio, February 12, 1896 (Folder 234)
- Webb, Sidney. Difficulties of Individualism. Fabian Tract 69. London, June 1896 (Folder 235)
- Atkinson, Edward. The Cost of a National Crisis. The Hell of War and Its Penalties. Two Treatises Suggested by the Appointment of a National Day of Thanksgiving by the President of the U. S. Boston, 1898 (Folder 236)
- Cromwell, John W. The American Negro Academy. Occasional Papers no. 9. The Early Negro Convention Movement. Washington, D.C., 1904 (Folder 237)
- Elliott, James. Rededication of the Paine Monument and the Assignment of Its Custody to the City of New Rochelle. A Record of eh Exercises and Report of the Speeches Delivered at the monument on Saturday, October 14, 1905 (Folder 238)
- Wyeth, John A. Gen. Robert E. Lee. Commemorative Address before the New York Southern Society, January 19, 1906 (Folder 239)
- Lee, James W. Abraham Lincoln: A Tribute Delivered February, 14, 1909, Upon the Occasion of a Special Memorial Service. Atlanta (Folder 240)
- Sherman, A. Outram. Thomas Paine Centennial Celebration: New Rochelle, June 5, 1909 (Folder 241)
- Sherman, A. Outram. Thomas Paine the Patriot, An Address Delivered Before the Huguenot Society of the New Rochelle at the Opening of the Paine House. New York, July 14, 1910 (Folder 242)
- McNeilly, James H. Religion and Slavery, a Vindication of the Southern Churches.. Nashville, Tennessee; Dallas Texas. Publishing House of the M.E. Church, 1911 (Folder 243)
- Miller, Harriet Parks. Pioneer Colored Christians. Clarksville, Tennessee, 1911 (Folder 244)
- Lozynsky, Michel. Comment les Polonais Comprennet leur Liberte. Lausanne, 1916 (Folder 245)